Zac Klammer

\kappa zklamm.github.io 🚨 zklamm@gmail.com 👂 Corpus Christi, TX

SUMMARY

I'm an experienced software engineer comfortable with backend, frontend, or managing cloud services (AWS). I recently created Maestro, an open source framework for serverless orchestration. Prior to working in software, I was a mechanical engineer working in the energy industry.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Co-founder & Software Engineer, *Maestro*

Jun 2020 – present

An open source framework for rapidly deploying and iterating on serverless workflows using AWS Step Functions, AWS Lambda, and AWS IAM

- Built easy-to-use CLI that abstracts away complex deployment logic, downloadable as an NPM package
- Optimized speed of workflow deployment and teardown by leveraging AWS SDKs and designing Maestro to execute commands asynchronously
- Created common templates for AWS Step Functions with the declarative, JSON-based Amazon States Language
- Wrote custom retry/backoff logic to ensure Lambda functions and state machines were created with proper roles
- Co-authored technical case study that explores the area of serverless orchestration, existing solutions in the problem space, and the process of creating Maestro -- maestro-framework.github.io
- Adhered to Agile best practices to develop the framework with two other remote engineers

Software Engineer, Baytek International

Jan 2019 - Feb 2020

- Built Microsoft Word plug-in for creating product analysis templates using Visual Studio Tools for Office
- Restructured user roles of company's core software offering to provide more granular permissions
- Assisted with integration of third party gas chromatograph software

Full Stack Web Developer, Self-Employed

Aug 2017 – present

Built several open source projects using technologies such as React, Redux, Rails, PostgreSQL, HTML, and CSS

- Reaction: A Trello-like application built with a React and Redux front end and Ruby on Rails back end
- Postit: A Reddit-like application built with Rails and PostgreSQL deployed to Heroku
- Airline Routes: An application that allows users to view and filter airline routes on a clickable SVG map

Project Manager & Mechanical Engineer, Southcross Energy

Mar 2014 - Aug 2017

• Managed multi-million dollar projects from initiation to completion

TECHNOLOGIES

Back End	Front End	Cloud	Other
 Node.js 	 JavaScript (ES5 & ES6+) 	 AWS Step Functions 	HTTP
• Ruby	 React/Redux 	 AWS Lambda 	• REST
• Rails	 jQuery 	 AWS IAM 	• OOP
 Sinatra 	 Handlebars.js 	 Heroku 	 Git/GitHub
• C#	 HTML/CSS 		
• SQL			

EDUCATION

Software Engineering, *Launch School* □

2017 – 2020 | Remote

An online school that teaches software fundamentals with a Mastery-Based Learning pedagogy launchschool.com/employers 🗷

Bachelor of Science - Mechanical Engineering, *Texas A&M University*

2008 – 2013 | College Station, TX

ORGANIZATIONS

Agape Ranch, Respite Care Provider

2018 - present

Trained and certified to provide temporary childcare for foster children